octranspo.com 2019-05-05

# OC Transpo - Privacy Policy

##  Purpose

The purpose of the statement is to inform website users of this site with regard to the collection and use of personally identifiable information. The following is not intended and should not be interpreted as a contract of any nature, either stated or implied.

##  Definition of Personally Identifiable Information

For the purposes of this statement "personally identifiable information" means any information relating to an identified or identifiable individual who is the subject of the information.

##  Use, collection, and retention of customer information on the OC Transpo web site

We only collect, retain and use personal information where we believe it is essential (and allowed by law) to administer our business and to provide products, services and other opportunities requested by our customers.

Our director limits employee access to personally identifiable information to only those employees who need access in order to perform their assigned duties. The director is instructed to enforce with its staff their responsibilities in protecting subscriber's information.

For each visitor, we do collect information about the Internet Protocol (IP) address, type browser used, the date and time of the visit, and the IP addresses of the locations to which the visitor linked during his or her visit to our Web site. This information is strictly used for statistical reporting purposes.

##  Restrictions on the disclosure of customer information

We do not sell or rent our users' information to any outside company or organization. We do not reveal specific information about users or other personally identifiable data to unaffiliated third parties for their independent use, except if required to do so by law.

##  Method of data collection

To collect data for statistical reporting purposes in order to improve our Web site, we are presently using an analytics software package called Google Analytics. We do not tie the data that is gathered by this software to any personally identifiable information and your anonymity and privacy is protected at all times. This data is collected by Google Analytics and produces reports that OC Transpo uses to improve its site. The information is kept private and not shared with anyone other than OC Transpo. To learn more about our Web analytics provider, please visit [www.google.com/analytic](http://www.google.com/analytics/ "Google Analytics web site").

We also use session-based cookies on the OC Transpo Web site to process requested services. A session-based cookie is a small file that stores information, but is discarded when the website user exits the browser. The OC Transpo Web site uses this method in order to collect data that is not personally identifiable, ensuring that it is used for statistical reporting purposes only.

##  Protection of information via established security procedures

Improvements in internet security occasionally cause older browsers to be unable to connect to [www.octranspo.com](http://www.octranspo.com/ "OC Transpo website"). This is for the protection of website users. If your browser is unable to make a secure connection, please consider upgrading your browser if you wish to access protected content.

##  Other Web Sites

Various Web sites may be linked through the portal. Visitors to those sites are advised to check the privacy statements of these sites and be cautious about providing personally identifiable information without a clear understanding of how the information will be used.
